otpp.com 2006-06-16

# OTPP - Privacy Code

|  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

|  |   | Privacy Code for members of the Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan | 

| 

---|---|---|---  
| At the Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan, we are dedicated to protecting your privacy and safeguarding your personal information. As part of our commitment, we have established this Privacy Code to govern our actions as they relate to the collection, use and disclosure of your information.

In developing our Privacy Code, we conducted a thorough review of our practices and re-examined why we collect, use and retain certain personal information.

We invite you to review the principles of our Privacy Code. Any concerns that you have regarding your personal information with us may be addressed to our Corporate Privacy Officer, who is responsible for monitoring and promoting the plan’s compliance with our Privacy Code.

Protecting the confidentiality of your personal information has always been fundamental to the Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan. With the Privacy Code, we renew our commitment to protect your privacy and safeguard your personal information at the plan.

The Principles  
  
Principle 1 - Accountability  
Principle 2 - Identifying Purposes  
Principle 3 - Consent  
Principle 4 - Limiting Collection  
Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention  
Principle 6 - Accuracy  
Principle 7 - Safeguarding Your Information  
Principle 8 - Openness  
Principle 9 - Individual Access to Information  
Principle 10 - Inquiries or Complaints  

| Principle 1 - Accountability  
The Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan is responsible for personal information under its control.  
---  
1.1| | The Corporate Privacy Officer of the Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan is accountable for monitoring and promoting compliance with our Privacy Code.  
1.2| | We have established policies and procedures to implement the Privacy Code, including:

  * policies and procedures to protect personal information we collect, use and disclose for plan administration 
  * requirements for other organizations that assist in plan administration 
  * procedures to respond to inquiries and complaints 
  * communications and training programs to inform our staff about privacy policies and practices 
  * information for plan members to explain our Privacy Code. 

Principle 2 - Identifying Purposes  
We collect personal information from you, your employer and others that we need to administer the plan, including to:  
| | 

  * accurately record and validate service as reported by employers 
  * invoice employers for required contributions 
  * determine benefit entitlements and process benefit applications 
  * communicate information about the plan 
  * understand and analyze your pension needs and develop services to inform you about how to preserve or improve your benefits 
  * assess the quality of the service we provide 
  * comply with applicable laws. 

Principle 3 - Consent  
We will obtain your express consent before collecting, using or disclosing your personal information for a purpose other than the administration of the plan, unless otherwise authorized by law.  
| |   
3.1| | Participation in the Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan is mandatory for all qualified teachers employed in education in Ontario. The information that you, your employer and others provide in relation to the plan is collected, used or disclosed under the authority of legislation such as the _Teachers’ Pension Act, the Pension Benefits Act_ and the _Income Tax Act_ (Canada). Your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information for the administration of the plan is implied and cannot be withdrawn.  
3.2| | We will ask for your express consent to the collection, use or disclosure of personal information for special promotions of products and services available from others. Consent to these promotions can be withdrawn at any time.  
Principle 4 - Limiting Collection  
We will collect only the personal information we need for the purposes described, and will do so only by fair and legal means.

Examples of the personal information we usually collect and maintain for use in administering the plan are available upon request.  
  
Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention  
We will use or disclose your personal information only for the purposes described, and retain it only for as long as is necessary for administration of the plan.

If we wish to use or disclose your information for a purpose other than the administration of the plan, we will obtain your express consent first, unless otherwise authorized by law.

We will not sell your personal information to other organizations or individuals.  
  
Principle 6 - Accuracy  
We will make every reasonable effort to keep your submitted personal information up-to-date and accurate.  
Principle 7 - Safeguarding Your Information  
We will protect your personal information with appropriate safeguards and security measures according to its sensitivity.

We will make every reasonable effort to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.  
  
Principle 8 - Openness  
Information about our privacy policies and practices concerning your personal information is available upon request.  
Principle 9 - Individual Access to Information  
Upon written request, we will advise you of the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information and provide you with access to that information. You may challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. We will record your concern if it is not resolved to your satisfaction.  
9.1| | We will respond to your access request within 30 days. There will be no charge for reasonable requests for such access.  
  
9.2| | Upon written request, we will disclose to you our record of your personal information along with an account of the source of the information, its use by us and its disclosure to third parties.  
9.3| | We may be unable to provide access to some or all of your information in certain circumstances including those where the information:

  * is unreasonably costly to provide 
  * contains references to other individuals 
  * cannot be disclosed for legal or security reasons 
  * is subject to solicitor-client and litigation privilege. 

Principle 10 - Inquiries or Complaints  
Any inquiry regarding our Privacy Code may be addressed to:

Ontario Teachers’ Pension Plan  
5650 Yonge Street,  
Toronto, ON M2M 4H5  
Attention: Client Services Department  
  
---  
Phone:| | (416) 226-2700 or 1-800-668-0105 (toll free)  
Fax:| | (416) 730-7807 or 1-800-949-8208 (toll free)  
E-mail:| | [inquiry@otpp.com](mailto:inquiry@otpp.com)  
  
Any complaint regarding compliance with our Privacy Code may be addressed to our Corporate Privacy Officer (Attention Plan Policy Department):  
Phone:| | (416) 730-3592 or 1-877-812-7989 ext. 3592 (toll free)  
Fax:| | (416) 730-3771 or 1-800-949-8208 (toll free)  
We will respond to all inquiries or complaints related to the handling of personal information. If a complaint is found to be justified, we will take appropriate measures. Complaint procedures are available from the Corporate Privacy Officer.  

  |   |   |    
---|---|---|---  
  |  Posted August 2005  |  TOP |    
  |   |   |
